[music]
I'm George Fam, the founder and CEO of
Stackback. When I'm not trying to create
like cartoon versions of myself, I'm
really into developer experience and
security, which are usually two things
that don't mix well. And we're building
an open source agent for DevOps. So the
we're trying to solve this problem
because like people as they realize on
on X that like LLM's are the worst at
the worst part at least like coding um
of the coding which is actually setup
and deployments and yeah a year later
this guy like literally gave up and said
okay it's AGI when LMS can do DevOps and
can configure my pipelines and deploy in
a cloud provider.
So we set up to to try fix this. There
are theoretical reasons why this
happens. I mean I'm sure you tried it
out if you're using agents like who's
using clock code or agents in general
who tried using agents to do devops work
yeah which is a big umbrella things okay
so one of the reasons is like lms they
suck at domain specific languages and
specifically knowledge that's fresh and
in DevOps infrastructure you have both
you have a lot of domain specific
languages and YAML scheas but they also
have knowledge that changes frequently
um that's one of the reason they're bad
at this so that's why we built stack
which is an open source agent in rust
that's trying to solve this and it
started doing that. So like the past two
weeks there are hundred of 100
developers that tried doing different
things with the agent and were
successful like contization of specific
stacks almost reach 100% success rate.
But like all this doesn't matter if you
something like that happens. So here I'm
not singling out replet this happened
with Amazon Q almost happened with
Amazon Q and GitHub copilot. Um, and it
happens with all of you like how many
times have cursor deleted something or
like deleted your file system or like
did something funny. So this happens and
this kills the trust we put in agents.
So if we're trying to make
infrastructure self-driving like we're
trying to do at Stackback, this just
kills the trust. It it's not possible.
So while we're trying to make agents
accurate and better infrastructure, we
found this bigger problem that needs
solving and that's what we're going to
talk about today. So if you stick
around, you would see me leaking our
production secrets on YouTube and nuking
our production infrastructure. So hang
on till the end cuz it's it's going to
be interesting. Yeah, that's your reward
for for attending this talk. So to start
off this, I imagine like you use agent,
you know at least a little bit how
agents work. So here we're going to
build a very simple threat model. And
threat model is basically you trying to
figure out everything that can go wrong
and then try to design your way around
it or like prevent it from going wrong.
So this is a very simple threat model.
Um here you would see like there are
components of building an agent. There's
an agent client or an MCP client if
you're using MCP which is the part that
takes user input and calls an LLM. And
there's also the tools which can be an
MCP set of MCP servers or it can be
built in the agent depending on which
agent you're using but like this general
is the same. And this is the security
context. Security context in thread
models are usually like a physical
machine or like an imaginary boundary of
things that have like high trust between
each other. So the agent trusts its own
tools. Assumption like it's an
assumption. And then the tools interact
with the local or remote device file
system. If it's a remote server over SSH
or SFTP or if it's a local machine if
you're working with it locally and then
through the network and MCP tools can go
like through the stack or system calls,
they can make external API calls to the
cloud and try do weird stuff like try
provision, destroy or like manage cloud
infrastructure or an external API. So
here we're going to share our experience
and the research of some of the stuff we
did on securing agents making them like
guided so they won't destroy stuff your
database for example but this applies if
you're also building agents that
interact with APIs in general. Uh so you
might find a little bit of this talk
useful. So the first threat we're
actually going to talk about is leaking
sensitive data to the LM provider. We're
not going to talk much about like
leaking stuff through LM tools because
in our case this was the main concern
because we were building the tools um at
least most of the tools the the people
need. Uh but like you would also be
worried about leaking secrets to the a
provider. Another threat is trying to
break production systems. So breaking
configurations on a live server or your
local machine and breaking the machine
for example. This is another threat. A
third threat is trying to modify cloud
resources which is the most juicy part
as you will see in the talk. um like
trying to destroy a bucket, delete a
database and so on. You see here I'm
highlighting the red lines because
usually when you're crossing like the
data flow is crossing a security
boundary, this is where most of the
interesting weird and scary stuff
happens. Um there's also injection, but
we're not going to talk about injection
mainly because a lot of people already
like looked into injection and what to
do about it and because it is a vector
to other threats. So injection in by
itself is not scary, but the things the
agent can do when it's injected is the
scary stuff. It can leak data, it can
break configurations, it can modify
resources in a tended way. So we're
going to take each of these three
threats and we're going to talk about
the design space, what we considered and
why it doesn't work. Some of the stuff
we considered and the actual
implementations we set alone. Some of
times it's not perfect, but sometimes
we're very happy with it. But that's the
goal of this talk like to spark this
discussion. Okay. So the first one thing
about leaking sensitive data what's the
most obvious thing to do not leave
secrets in plain text right very obvious
but like we can do that like we still
use M files we still somehow need to
generate these secrets to set them in
the first place and if you want your
agent to run your infrastructure
autonomously it would have to generate
secrets and actually use them so this
doesn't work like if it had worked we
wouldn't have any of these issues or
like no OpenAI API keys on GitHub
A second solution would be to redact
secrets. Who thinks this is a good uh
idea?
Please raise your hand. Okay, so at
first it seems like a good idea, but if
you want your agent to actually work
with the secrets, like compare secrets
to the buck stuff, it wouldn't work
because the secrets are all redacted.
Like how would the agent be able to
reason about the secrets, set them, and
compare them to the buck stuff if it's
all redacted?
A third solution which is like the most
obvious one and the most like popular
one is to ask the LLM nicely to handle
the secret properly and yeah you know
how that ends. So let's not get there.
So what we decided to do is to use
secret substitution. So we detect the
secrets. So what we did here is we took
the git leaks public um rule set and
then we implemented that in rust because
we wanted to be implemented in the
agent. We didn't want to have a lot of
third party dependencies and it's
actually open source. It's Apache 2.0
And what it does is between the agent
and its tools which is the hands. So the
agent is the brain. It thinks about
stuff and it takes actions with the with
the tools. And between the tools and the
agent we inserted this secret
substitution layer which is like this
ether sort of weird laser boundary that
turns the secret into a unique ID and
then shows this ID or placeholder to the
agent. The agent works with the unique
placeholder and then writes it back and
whenever it's written back the it would
substitute it back. So yeah uh a demo is
uh worth a thousand words. So let me
show you. So here I started a stack pack
instance on our live production
connected to our live production
environment. Whoa.
So I asked it like what permissions you
have in AWS and you can see this is not
a secret per se but it started already
redacting things um like the account ID.
Uh here I'm running in privacy mode
that's why it's redacting account ids
and public IPs but these are not secrets
but yeah so you can see like how it
looks that when it's actually like being
parsed by the remember this like um I
now have administrative access to my
account this is important for later on
and then I can ask it to list my EC2s
and because privacy mode is on the
public IP should be hidden and yeah I
can ask it to do something like um dump
the i eval
uh public IP to a file.
>> Sorry.
>> Yeah, sure.
So it dumped the stuff in a file. You
can see how the LLM sees things. But
like if you go here and we try to look
at it, you see the actual IP because
this is like the weird layer we talked
about like it translates the secrets
into IPs and so on and it remembers the
stuff and this is like for the moment
it's stored in local file system. This
is open source you can check it out but
in the future it can integrate with
third like um other secret managers.
So future work here we are bubbling like
refactoring this into a local MCP proxy.
So you can have this secret substitution
with any thirdparty MCP servers you can
use, not just like the tools we built
stack pack initially. But there's also
something very interesting. There's a
project on GitHub called fuzzforge that
compared using LLM with rules like
deterministic static analysis tools like
GitLinks and Truffle Hog to do this. And
LM are actually much better at detecting
more secrets. But then like the first
glance like you think this is stupid
like we're trying to prevent LM from
seeing the secret based on our thread
model. But like again take this further
like what if we can take this and build
a small language model or fine tune a
small language model that can run
locally on your machine to augment these
tools because according to this LMS are
much better at detecting like well
hidden secret or like dynamically
constructed secrets than git leaks and
git leaks has like yeah there are some
caveats to the rules they don't always
work so this would be perfect. So this
is something we're going to explore in
the future is take building smaller
language models that can augment these
uh static analysis tools to figure out
like harder to find secrets and redact
them before they go to the lams on the
cloud.
So the second threat breaking
configuration files. So the first
solution is to codify everything like do
turn everything into infrastructure as
code and there's a reason reason there
are like five or six companies trying to
help people codify infrastructure like
companies are never done codifying
infrastructure and there's always like
an escape hatch where you do stuff
manually so this doesn't always work
like this works in the perfect world but
like in reality it's it's very hard
second thing is to back up everything
which also works in in like in
theoretically but in practice yeah
there's a reason why ransomwarees are
still like a threat is we don't all back
up things.
Another one is file system overlays.
This is a perfect way to do this where
you see a true like change and look like
edit stuff on an overlay and then
persist them later on. So you can like
rever these changes but requires root
access. So this is the perfect uh
solution for this problem at least from
our perspective but we're still
investigating this. So we didn't end up
in like implementing this um as the
current solution. What we did is we
built recoverable file system operations
which is not perfect. I mean the LM can
still like decide not to obey you like
the data gif I I I showed you earlier u
and it feels trivial initially but like
there's some nuances here so for create
it's very easy like you can just delete
the file created by exploring the
history uh like looking to the lm
history but string replace you would
think it's trivial just like reverse the
operations but it's not like this is an
example like this like four or five line
Python code if you're trying to replace
hello with hey
it would replace it correctly. But if
we're trying to reverse the operands, it
wouldn't work. And this is one example
of a lot of examples. So this like if I
can yeah this would output false. Um and
there are a lot of examples where this
doesn't work. So the way we got around
this is we the string replace to output
is actually um a udiff of the operation.
So then it's perfectly reversible
because it includes context on where the
stuff changed. Uh so you can actually
reverse it. And the same thing with
backups by removing files. We added a
remove tool. I know the LLM doesn't
necessarily have to uh respect that but
yeah that backups remote files when the
editing operation is done on a remote
system and backs them locally if we're
working on a local system because people
use stack pack over SSH a lot you can
see here so
remove the file you created
it also works for directories
recursively
so I called the remote tool
and in the context it returns like the
tool result it returns the backup um
location. So here if I list it there's
nothing and then store it.
I know you don't have to use an LM to
restore it but like yeah
now you can see the file is back. This
works for directories as well. It's
basically like reimplementing trash
again uh in the terminal.
Yeah. So for future work we want to
revisit overlays find ways to do this in
user space. Uh but there's also some
interesting things happening like agent
FS which build helps you build like an
overlay like our file system within
SQLite which is super cool like so then
you can inspect all the operations rever
it and so on. So this is also something
I just read about and I want to dig
deeper uh into.
Okay, the third one and the final one
and the most interesting one like you
see we went down a rabbit hole in this
one is preventing agents from actually
destroying your cloud infrastructure
which is like the most scary thing like
I would I wouldn't use stack packback
myself if this didn't work because how
can you rely on agent to investigate
something in the background using a CLI
tool if you're not sure what it's going
to do um so the most obvious solution as
well here is give agents this privilege
access and there's a reason why this
have been very hard to do for humans for
years like it's very hard to figure out
beforehand what kind of access you would
need before you need it because like if
you're in the middle of investigating an
incident and you turns out you give
yourself only read access and you can't
revert stuff then it's a it's a bad
thing like you you need this access but
also because you have a lot of APIs like
if you have a cloud native environment
you have a kubernetes access you have
AWS access uh GitHub access so all these
kind of like it's very hard to manage
these and there are companies like built
exclusively for managing access across
different APIs so this is very tough to
do in practice so we We need to add
security in depth. Like even if we get
to do least privilege access and we want
these agents to be autonomous and
capable and be able to change cloud, how
should we how can we control this?
The second solution which is the most
popular um is whitelisting blacklisting
commands and using hooks to help you
prevent the agent from doing destructive
things. Um, agents are super creative
like um I gave an earlier talk in in
like in the um like the cloud native
meetup in New York earlier this year and
we were forcing agents to generate 100%
valid Terraform syntax. So it can only
talk in terapform like it can't do
anything else and when we asked it to
define itself or like to do something it
was not a supposed to be able to do by
generating terapform it generated like a
null resource that echoes a script in
the file system and then runs the
script.
They're really hacky. Like they're
they're super creative. So if you try
blacklist or whitelist a command, it
would just like yeah find another way to
do this, right? A Python script or
download a third party tool to do this
and so on. They're very creative. So
blacklisting, whitelisting,
yeah, it doesn't work all the time. It
doesn't give you the trust or the
guarantees you need to be able to do
this.
A third solution is using code
sandboxes. Like who thinks this is a
good solution?
This is where our threat model is
actually important. So remember in the
threat model, we were not trying to
prevent like in this case, we were
trying to prevent the agent from
destroying cloud resources over an API.
The sandbox wouldn't prevent you from
doing that. Like if you if you're
running this on a via virtual machine
and you give it an API key to the API,
it will still be able to make API calls.
So this coding sandboxes at least how we
like how most people define it now it's
not enough because according to our
threat model the one we started with we
want to prevent it from making external
calls to break things not local file
system changes right so this doesn't
work like people think this would work
but it doesn't in practice
another fourth base solution is using AI
based detection who thinks this is a
good option
okay I'm giving myself away like
[laughter] okay So here for example like
for AI based detection people build
specialized models that can detect with
99.9999%
accuracy that these commands are
malicious or something is going wrong so
you can prevent it and so on. The issue
here is of adversarial machine learning
which is the domain of finding a single
example that would break a neural
network and make it do the right wrong
thing. Either um it's a language model
and trick it into bypassing the
guardrails like trying to jailbreak JPT
or a vision model like this one. So one
of the oldest papers I think it was in
2017 um it resulted um a neural net to
mistake a hamster for a nipple. And this
is not very malicious, but you get the
idea. Like it's very easy to change a
single pixel in the image to mclassify
um a command that is actually yeah
benign while it's malicious. And
something more dangerous happened a
couple of years later in 2021 um which
you can 3D print actual objects that are
adversarial examples to self-driving
vehicles. This would attack like um
multi-ensor fusion networks where like
they mix lidars with images with a lot
of other sensors and they like
researchers claimed for a long time that
this makes the network more robust. But
actually like 3D printing a small like
white cube like that one would trick the
self-driving vehicle or this model into
like taking actions the attackers
intended to or design this model for it.
So there always be an adversarial
examples at least theoretically that
would be able to do that. And the reason
you would find it and how you' find it
is actually training another network to
do this. So this is always bypassable
like you can't trust this 100%. That's
why most of the techniques we're using
in this talk is all the are all
deterministic.
So what did we end up doing here? We
ended up designing uh something we call
warden which is a transparent proxy that
like soaks in all the traffic from the
agent and the MCP tools and then applies
policies in Cedar like what Ry mentioned
and Cedar is like has some nice
properties. We still haven't made use of
all of them, but it's very simple to
define a policy that like blocks every
all access in just like 30 lines of
code. Um, and would prevent your agent
its tools or all any of its dependencies
from making destructive stuff on the
network because like intercepts it
locally on your machine before it goes
out of the network to do stuff. Um, and
you can see here like this is the 30
line policy and it even includes a rule
that would allow the agent to call back
to the stack pack API because this is
where we do the inference.
So this 30 line rule allows you to work
on AWS without breaking anything. But
let's let's try that. I like I promised
you we would try to break our production
infrastructure and let's do it. So nuke
all the EC2s. Can you see this?
Yeah. So let's try destroy everything.
My team would not be very happy.
>> Just do it.
>> Yeah. Okay.
Z Cloud thinks I'm crazy. Okay. Yeah. So
here Warden intercepted the network
request to destroy this instance and
prevented it and echoed back. Okay. This
is denied. This is not allowed. And this
is done on the network layer. So
regardless of what kind of tool you use,
so you can use a CLI, custom Python
script, terapform, it doesn't matter.
Like this is done on a lower layer and
you're sure this policy engine will work
every single time and it's yeah, we call
it network sandboxing.
So there's still more things to do. Um
here mainly the issue is the UX like I
had to start worden like stack pack with
all its dependencies inside a single
sandbox. But I want to scope this down
like what if you can create a sandbox
for a single command or like a single
MCP server instead of everything. So
then you can do a mix of safe operations
and unsafe stuff. Um we want to allow
people to turn it on and off mid
session. Want to be able to customize
the policies on the fly because like
Cedar is really nice. Like if you have
two or three versions of a policy, you
can actually decide uh deterministically
whether they're equivalent or not or
like subsets or not. So you can allow
LLM to write policies on the fly and
have some guarantees about them.
Finally, we want to try turn this into a
standard. Um, so I want to collaborate
with people building agents to improve
this experience and have some sort of
spec on how to build these kind of
sandboxes and the different kinds of
sandboxes. So this is an invitation like
come talk to me so we can try figure out
like ways we can make this better and
like we can reuse this in other projects
as well. So I'm chatting out to a
couple. I think there's an engineer at
Enthropic that built a similar sandbox,
but like in ways it like it's not a
transparent proxy like it relies on CLI
tools using like respecting system proxy
settings which are not possible in all
HTTP clients. That's why we need
transparent proxy. There's also strong
DM. Uh they just like released something
called leash which does exactly the same
thing in terms of network sandboxing but
they also have some stuff going on and
like intercepting system to calls to
file system changes as well. So we're
trying to bring these efforts together
by talking to these people and you if
you're interested so we can reuse this
stuff.
Okay. So reach out to me on LinkedIn to
discuss this or like hang around and
yeah thank you all for having the
patience. [applause]
[music]
Heat. Heat.